

Craig Carter

Phone: (562) 547-7845

Email: craig_carter@apple.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/craig-carter42

Profile

With over six years of experience as a technician, I am a confident self-starter who works well independently and can thrive working with teams who deliver quality products and services. I am driven by my passion for technology and problem-solving in fast-paced work environments.

Work Experience

Genius, Apple — March 2017-Present

- · Focuses on driving results at the Genius Bar to maximize customer service and technical results.
- Customer focused and strives to provide outstanding experiences through strong customer focus.
- Uses problem solving skills to triage advanced issues and provide multiple solutions.
- Utilizes keen eye for detail when completing hardware repairs to maintain company standards.
- Partners with management to innovate around repair strategies to improve customer experience.
- Documents issues to create accurate repair history for customer devices.

Intern with Platform Restore QA, Apple — January 2019-July 2019

- Monitored automation results to insure no regressions were induced in daily build.
- Triaged failures to determine the source of the error and sent bug report to responsible teams.
- · Maintained and improved the automation infrastructure in the lab.
- Performed manually testing of new software to check for graphical anomalies during the update process.
- Completed preflight tests for side builds to validate changes before being merged to mainline.
- · Worked with three separate automation frameworks and contributed enhancements to existing automation code.
- · Used Python to write an automated test to simulate poor WiFi conditions during updates.
- · Created a Python tool to help find update assets during manual testing.

Technical Specialist, Apple - April 2014-March 2017

- · Achieved session productivity to positively impact customer timeliness and access.
- Supported on average 30 customers a day at the Genius Bar.
- Utilized diagnostic tools and triaging skills to provide solutions to customers.
- Educated customers on how to use technology and taught new features.
- · Wrote meticulous notes to help track customer issues and creating paperwork for module repairs.

Tier II Technical Support Engineer, Leap Motion — Jan 2013-Sep 2013

- · Provided phone and email support to customers experiencing issues.
- Worked with a team to troubleshoot technical issues.
- Escalated bugs to the appropriate department for further review.
- Documented and managed customer interactions using internal CRM system.
- · Assisted with identifying trends with customer questions and concerns.

Software and Hardware Skills

Python, Bash, Shell Scripting, Command Line, Git, Ansible, Docker, Nginx, Linux, Unix, Radar, Apple (all platforms), Raspberry Pi, Arduino, Teensy Board

Technical Skills

Problem Solving, Grey & Black Box Testing, Automation Triage, Collecting and Analyzing Crash Logs

Education

UC Berkeley Extension | Certificate Program in Software Development and Programming (Expected completion June 2022)

Certifications

(ACMT) Apple Certified Mac Technician (ACIT) Apple Certified iOS Technician